Hongkai Liu

liuhkai@gmail.com 438-990-6099 Montreal, QC, Canada

SUMMARY

10+ years' experience in software development and testing. Solid knowledge on Java programming. Skills of Shell, Python, Ansible and GoLang. Hands-on experience with Docker and Kubernetes. Familiar with TDD, BDD, and test automation. Involved in development and maintenance of CI/CD tools.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Red Hat Canada LTD., Canada.

Apr. 2019 to now

Software Engineer

• Devops on <u>Prow-based CI system</u> for <u>OpenShift</u>.

Environment: IntelliJ/VSCode, GoLang, Python, Shell, Github, Jira, Kubernetes, and OpenShift.

Red Hat Canada LTD., Canada.

Jun. 2017 to Apr. 2019

Quality Engineer

- Development of system tests on OpenShift clusters on AWS, GCE and Azure. Automation of end-to-end OpenShift installation and other tests with Shell, Python, and Ansible.
- Tests on native container storage solutions such as <u>Gluster</u> and <u>Rook-Ceph</u>.

Environment: IntelliJ/VSCode, Shell/Python/GoLang, Ansible, Github, Jenkins/Travis-CI, Jira, Coveralls, Docker, Kubernetes, and OpenShift.

Elits Canada Inc., Canada.

Mar. 2015 to Jun. 2017

Software Developer (Consultant at Ericsson)

- Development, support and troubleshooting of <u>Gerrit</u> service and Jenkins service.
- Implementation and testing of <u>Eiffel</u>, an integrated CI system. Performing tests againsting containerized environment.

Environment: Core Java 7/8, Springboot/Guice, Cucumber, IntelliJ, Bash/Python, Gerrit/Github, Maven/Gradle, Jenkins/Travis-CI, Jira/Tuleap, SonarQube/Coveralls, Docker, and Vagrant.

Lenovo Corp. Research & Development, China.

Nov. 2013 to Nov. 2014

Development Architect

- Development of the Data Reporting System based on Kafka, Logstash, and Hadoop-based tools.
- Implementation of Real-Time Monitoring System which integrates Kafka and mdrill.

Environment: Core Java 6, Android SDK, MySQL, CDH, mdrill, Redis, Kafka, Logstash, Spring, MyBatis, Netty, JUnit, Eclipse, Linux, SVN, Gerrit, Maven, and Hudson.

Beijing Leadtone Wireless Co., Ltd, China.

Sep. 2010 to Sep. 2013

Senior Software Developer

- Algorithm design and implementation to provide intelligent polling time of POP3 mailboxes.
- Protocol design of LeadTone push platform. Prototyping Android applications on the platform with Android SDK.

Environment: Core Java 6, Android SDK, MySQL, Spring, Hibernate, JUnit, Eclipse, Linux, SVN, Maven, and Continuum.

CERTIFICATE

• VMware Certified Professional on vSphere 5 (VCP5) in Aug. 2012.

• IELTS: 7.5 in Sep. 2013.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science, Dresden University of Technology, Germany.
M.S. in Computer Science, Dresden University of Technology, Germany.
B.E. in Computer Science, Anshan Science and Technology University, China.
Jul. 2002